<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>policy on synthDIY.space</title><link>https://musicminister.github.io/github.io/tags/policy/</link><description>Recent content in policy on synthDIY.space</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2023 Eugene Huo | Powered by Hugo</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 08:06:41 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://musicminister.github.io/github.io/tags/policy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Comment Policy</title><link>https://musicminister.github.io/github.io/comment-policy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 08:06:41 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://musicminister.github.io/github.io/comment-policy/</guid><description>#Community Guidelines#
##synthDIY.space community standards, participations guidelines, and moderation goals##
###Commenter community guidelines###
synthDIY.space welcomes diverse opinions and discussion, but most importantly we value constructive comments and interactions that are relevant to the discussion, and respectful to our fellow readers and writers.
There is zero tolerance for comments we believe to be insulting or inappropriate, trolling, or have potential for legal action.
Commenters can flag potentially inappropriate comments for review, out of concern for others, or due to personal offence.</description><content>&lt;p>#Community Guidelines#&lt;/p>
&lt;p>##synthDIY.space community standards, participations guidelines, and moderation goals##&lt;/p>
&lt;p>###Commenter community guidelines###&lt;/p>
&lt;p>synthDIY.space welcomes diverse opinions and discussion, but most importantly we value constructive comments and interactions that are relevant to the discussion, and respectful to our fellow readers and writers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is zero tolerance for comments we believe to be insulting or inappropriate, trolling, or have potential for legal action.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Commenters can flag potentially inappropriate comments for review, out of concern for others, or due to personal offence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can flag concerns via the menu next to a potentially offensive comment, or email us via our contact page.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>###How to comment###&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our comments run on the third-party disqus platform, which requires you to set up an account. You can register a Disqus profile either directly with Disqus, or with your Facebook, Twitter or Google accounts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Disqus does not require you use your real name, however, we prefer commenters use their real name as it increases the likelihood of mature and accountable behaviour. Importantly, using your real name is not a requirement and we recognize there are valid reasons for using a pseudonym.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>###Keeping it friendly###&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hopefully our comment forums help us and others broaden our knowledge, understanding, and passion for synthesizers, electronics and DIY.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Discussion and debate are welcome, but comments that include personal attacks on another reader or writer are not acceptable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While appreciating there will be, at times, different points of view, we reserve the right to caution commenters openly, delete, edit or modify a thread that breaches our guidelines, and suspend or ban repeat offenders.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition, we will not tolerate racism, sexism, homophobia or other forms of hate-speech, or contributions that could be interpreted as such.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>###Clarity and intent###&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The tone of the written word is not always obvious, so stop and think twice before publishing your comment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>‘Shouting’ – letters, words, or sentences in capital letters – and the use of emojis, other symbols, and inappropriate language are frowned upon because they are designed to make one comment stand out from others.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Use of these and similar techniques could lead to the comment being deleted, edited, or modified at the discretion of our moderation team. Repeat offenders may face have face suspension or a permanent ban.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>###User images (avatars)###&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Distasteful imagery in Disqus user photo/picture profiles (also known as an avatar) is banned on synthDIY.space.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Examples of banned content include sexually explicit, suggestive or revealing imagery; depictions of violence or gore; crude imagery; the celebration or depiction of criminals or criminal activity; propaganda.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>###Back-up profiles###&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Commenters are asked to maintain one profile only, and our moderators flag the IP addresses of repeat offenders.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Repeat offenders with multiple accounts will be banned from our comments section.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>###Links###&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Posting links in comments is allowed to refer to other articles or other pertinent and relevant data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Comments that include links will be reviewed and potentially withheld pending review.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>###Who moderates synthDIY.space?###&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The monitoring and moderation of discussion in the comments section of synthDIY.space are done by the team.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Footnote: These guidelines may be revised or updated at any time, without notice.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>