<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>notes on synthDIY.space</title><link>https://musicminister.github.io/github.io/tags/notes/</link><description>Recent content in notes on synthDIY.space</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2023 Eugene Huo | Powered by Hugo</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 22:56:09 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://musicminister.github.io/github.io/tags/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Build Notes Nlc Lux</title><link>https://musicminister.github.io/github.io/posts/build-notes-nlc-lux/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 22:56:09 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://musicminister.github.io/github.io/posts/build-notes-nlc-lux/</guid><description>This is a pretty unique and simple module consisting of two light sensitive photodiodes producing CV outputs depending on how much light they receive. The gain can be increased by increasing the value of the gain resistor.
I made a video using two lux modules to simulate some bird songs, using them like a kind of optical theremin.
Making Bird Sounds and Songs with Eurorack
Build Notes:
- I experimented with 4 different values of gain resistor: 1M, 2.</description><content>&lt;p>This is a pretty unique and simple module consisting of two light sensitive photodiodes producing CV outputs depending on how much light they receive. The gain can be increased by increasing the value of the gain resistor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I made a video using two lux modules to simulate some bird songs, using them like a kind of optical theremin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/6OflJaoHDFE">Making Bird Sounds and Songs with Eurorack&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Build Notes:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- I experimented with 4 different values of gain resistor: 1M, 2.2M, 3.0M and 4.7M Ohms which will be useful in giving a different response under the same lighting conditions, or to choose one to use depending on how bright or dark the performance environment is&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- upon testing I thought I had messed it up somehow because the CV outputs were extremely &amp;lsquo;dirty&amp;rsquo;, when I used them in a 1v/oct VCO input the sounds was very noisy. I realized that it was actually the lights causing the noise, because I have LED pot lights in my house and they must be flickering and causing the CV output to look like a square wave! Shining a flashlight with an incandescent bulb on the modules resulted in a smooth tone with no noise. Fascinating!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- this is a build involving SMD components, including a SOIC TL072. I used the iron for this one, I&amp;rsquo;ll probably break out the paste and air for a more involved build. It is a pretty good first time module for SMD, as it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have very many components at all.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Build Notes Amazing Synth Noodle Toaster</title><link>https://musicminister.github.io/github.io/posts/build-notes-amazingsynth-noodle-toaster/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 15:03:09 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://musicminister.github.io/github.io/posts/build-notes-amazingsynth-noodle-toaster/</guid><description>The Amazing Synth Noodle Toaster is an iteration on the Mutable Instruments Module Tester designed by Émilie Gillet.
Several problems were faced during the development of our Eurorack modules:
How to power and test a module during development? Bench-top power supplies are cumbersome (especially for projects requiring 3 supply rails) and standard test equipment is sometimes useless or frustrating for quantities like musical notes or V/Oct scales. On the other extreme of the scale, who would run the risk of putting a half-built prototype in a rack loaded with thousands of euros worth of modules?</description><content>&lt;p>The Amazing Synth Noodle Toaster is an iteration on the &lt;a href="https://pichenettes.github.io/mutable-instruments-diy-archive/module_tester/">Mutable Instruments Module Tester&lt;/a> designed by Émilie Gillet.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Several problems were faced during the development of our Eurorack modules:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>How to power and test a module during development? Bench-top power supplies are cumbersome (especially for projects requiring 3 supply rails) and standard test equipment is sometimes useless or frustrating for quantities like musical notes or V/Oct scales. On the other extreme of the scale, who would run the risk of putting a half-built prototype in a rack loaded with thousands of euros worth of modules?&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>What kind of setup to use for factory testing?&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>How to take a project away from the lab without carrying heaps of &amp;ldquo;dependencies&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>We solved this the Mutable Instruments way, rolling up our sleeves and designing a simple box able to provide power and all kinds of test signals (clocks, gates, CVs, audio tones) to a module. This tool is made available under cc-by-sa (hardware) and GPL (firmware) licenses.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Amazing Synth in the UK have taken this design and produced a nice clone of the PCB, as well as a custom fitted case made from cut acrylic, in various colours.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I spent a very enjoyable day putting this together. I have since used it to test a VCA module that I put together, and it would make light work of VCO calibration, for example.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Build Notes:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- I chose the wrong kind of pin header to attach the LCD screen, so mine is sitting up off the PCB supported only by the pins. Probably not a problem as long as I don&amp;rsquo;t push hard on the screen. It&amp;rsquo;s supposed to sit on the PCB, but I like it slightly raised as it&amp;rsquo;s more visible through the opening in the case&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- The bourns trimmers on the upper right are quite tall and prevent the case from sitting down flat, it would be nice to maybe either have an opening for them so the case can screw down on the standoffs without pushing on the trimmer tops&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- the acrylic case has indented print labelling (a la D&amp;amp;D dice) so I filled them in with a white crayon, I think it looks nice, it pops against the blue colour&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- I made a mistake in putting it together, in that I did not fully fill with solder the joints for the power connector. I don&amp;rsquo;t know why, I thought I could just partially solder them but the unit wouldn&amp;rsquo;t power on when I tried it the first time. After fully filling the joints it powered on successfully&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Build Notes Zlob Vnicursal</title><link>https://musicminister.github.io/github.io/posts/build-notes-zlob-vnicursal/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:01:41 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://musicminister.github.io/github.io/posts/build-notes-zlob-vnicursal/</guid><description>Zlob Modular is the work of Keven Michael-Onur Kalaycıoğlu-Żłobnicki. Their module called the Vnicursal is 6 VCAs in an 8HP wide module, what&amp;rsquo;s not to like! Each input has a CV and then the output, either individual or there is a summed out at the bottom if you want to use it as a mixer for audio. VCAs can be used for much more than audio, and they are a must have module in every rack.</description><content>&lt;p>Zlob Modular is the work of Keven Michael-Onur Kalaycıoğlu-Żłobnicki. Their module called the &lt;a href="https://zlobmodular.com/product/vnicursal-vca/">Vnicursal&lt;/a> is 6 VCAs in an 8HP wide module, what&amp;rsquo;s not to like! Each input has a CV and then the output, either individual or there is a summed out at the bottom if you want to use it as a mixer for audio. VCAs can be used for much more than audio, and they are a must have module in every rack.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Notes:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- this is the latest revision, v666 (haha) which utilizes resistor arrays to cut down on the number of individual components, much easier to work with. More modules should start using arrays if they are sticking with thru hole designs and need lots of resistors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- this tested out great on the workbench except for channel 6, upon re-inspection I discovered I had skipped two of the leads! Haha, that&amp;rsquo;s not going to work! Did those right quick and all 6 channels working perfectly. Hurray for testing!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- Zlob has provided a very good photo build guide that you can follow along with as you go, and it shows you where each new component goes&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- it&amp;rsquo;s important to get the headers at the correct angles, precisely perpendicular to the board, otherwise you&amp;rsquo;ll have difficulty mating up the two boards after wards&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- with things like IC sockets, I like to solder one pin, and then with the iron still touching, press down (or up) with my finger to make sure the assembly is lying flat on the board, before removing the iron from the pin. Tape is required to keep the part on the board before you flip it over, but sometimes even tape can sag.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>