<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on synthDIY.space</title><link>https://musicminister.github.io/github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on synthDIY.space</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2023 Eugene Huo | Powered by Hugo</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 14:03:45 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://musicminister.github.io/github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Inventory Management Do I Need It?</title><link>https://musicminister.github.io/github.io/posts/inventory-management-need-it/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 14:03:45 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://musicminister.github.io/github.io/posts/inventory-management-need-it/</guid><description>A review of partsbox.io &amp;ldquo;For every minute spent organizing, an hour is earned&amp;rdquo; - Anon.
When I started with DIY keeping track of components was pretty simple, the parts all came with the kits! But after branching out into sourcing components on my own, I definitely started thinking about how to organize things.
Abe over at AI Synthesis recommends the &amp;ldquo;bags in bags&amp;rdquo; method of parts storage, which is mostly how I do it.</description><content>&lt;h2 id="a-review-of-partsboxiohttppartsboxio">A review of &lt;a href="http://partsbox.io">partsbox.io&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;For every minute spent organizing, an hour is earned&amp;rdquo; - Anon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I started with DIY keeping track of components was pretty simple, the parts all came with the kits! But after branching out into sourcing components on my own, I definitely started thinking about how to organize things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Abe over at AI Synthesis recommends the &amp;ldquo;bags in bags&amp;rdquo; method of parts storage, which is mostly how I do it. &lt;a href="https://aisynthesis.com/how-to-store-diy-synth-parts/">Check out the method as he describes it on his site&lt;/a>. So that&amp;rsquo;s how to store things, but I quickly realized that I wanted to have a way to know where and how many of each part I had on hand, so that I could know before I started a build that I had all the parts on hand, without having to do a manual search for each item on the Bill of Materials (or BOM).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is where &amp;lsquo;inventory management&amp;rsquo; comes in. Do a google and you&amp;rsquo;ll find a lot of solutions for inventory management, but there are are only a handful that are geared towards hobbyist electronics DIY&amp;rsquo;ers. And of those handful, only one has a free tier that isn&amp;rsquo;t limited in the areas where it counts: &lt;a href="http://partsbox.io">partsbox.io&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The role of inventory management is relatively simple but powerful. You enter the parts as you receive them, tracking the name of the part, the number of parts, how much they cost (that&amp;rsquo;s optional but useful), and which storage &amp;lsquo;container&amp;rsquo; they are in. So a new entry would look something like: 1K Ohm 1/4W Metal Film Resistor, 100 units at $0.03 each, in the &amp;ldquo;ones&amp;rdquo; resistor bag.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Partsbox also allows the connection of a USB handheld scanner like the kind they use at checkout counters, which are surprisingly cheap to buy online. Any old one will do, and if the part comes in a package with a barcode (like from mouser, for example) then scanning and entering new parts is pretty efficient. Parts from tayda or elsewhere without a barcode will require manual input of the part name. Partsbox offers a the ability to search for a part using Octapart, and you can enter a specific part that way. For example, a resistor made by Taiyo Yuden. Or you can choose to just enter a generic part name, like in my example above, if you will be sourcing the same components from different manufacturers. The ubiquitous 1K resistor really doesn&amp;rsquo;t need a super specific entry.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once a part is entered into the system, you are able to see your stock levels, where a part is stored, and even a running tally of the value of your parts that you have on hand. But where the real power of system comes in is creating projects and tracking builds.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Each Project in partsbox, for me, is one eurorack module. Fill in the BOM for the project, and partsbox can then know how many of whichever component is needed for that project. Then when you click the &amp;ldquo;Build&amp;rdquo; button, partsbox will compare the BOM against the inventory, let you know if you have all the parts needed, and if not it will alert you as to which parts and how many you need to buy. If you have all the parts on hand, confirming the build will take those parts out of inventory and commit them to the build.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I don&amp;rsquo;t have to wonder if I have enough TL072 chips on hand to make the next module, I can just check the project and it will let me know. It will even tally the cost of the components used in any particular project, if you want to know how much is being sunk into any given module.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also don&amp;rsquo;t have to speculatively buy extra components in the hope that &amp;lsquo;someday&amp;rsquo; I might use them, I can just get the parts that are needed. Of course knowing that buying in bulk usually saves money, partsbox can also show you how many of what component is used in every project, so you can have that information when you make your order.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Are there any cons? There is a time component, of course, entering components is time consuming, especially if you have a lot of parts on hand to start with. It would be ideal to get into something like this from the beginning, so that you enter as you receive parts. You&amp;rsquo;ll have to factor in whether the time doing the initial inventory will be worth the payoff in the end.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The free tier doesn&amp;rsquo;t support automatic ordering, which sounds really cool. You also can&amp;rsquo;t just import a BOM from, say, a CSV file, unless it came from KiCad first.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even with these limitations, I&amp;rsquo;m finding the information that partsbox gives me to be invaluable, and it is streamlining my ordering to the correct amount of any given component that I need.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s amazing that they&amp;rsquo;ve kept it free for single user hobbyist types like me, and I hope this mini-review encourages you to give it a try.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Got questions? Leave me a comment and I&amp;rsquo;ll try to answer them!&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Build Notes Nlc Lux</title><link>https://musicminister.github.io/github.io/posts/build-notes-nlc-lux/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 22:56:09 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://musicminister.github.io/github.io/posts/build-notes-nlc-lux/</guid><description>The LUX module by nonlinearcircuits is a pretty unique and simple module consisting of two light sensitive photodiodes producing CV outputs depending on how much light they receive. The gain can be increased by increasing the value of the gain resistor.
I made a video using two lux modules to simulate some bird songs, using them like a kind of optical theremin.
Making Bird Sounds and Songs with Eurorack
Build Notes:</description><content>&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://www.nonlinearcircuits.com/modules/p/lux?rq=lux">LUX module by nonlinearcircuits&lt;/a> is a pretty unique and simple module consisting of two light sensitive photodiodes producing CV outputs depending on how much light they receive. The gain can be increased by increasing the value of the gain resistor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I made a video using two lux modules to simulate some bird songs, using them like a kind of optical theremin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/6OflJaoHDFE">Making Bird Sounds and Songs with Eurorack&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Build Notes:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- I experimented with 4 different values of gain resistor: 1M, 2.2M, 3.0M and 4.7M Ohms which will be useful in giving a different response under the same lighting conditions, or to choose one to use depending on how bright or dark the performance environment is&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- upon testing I thought I had messed it up somehow because the CV outputs were extremely &amp;lsquo;dirty&amp;rsquo;, when I used them in a 1v/oct VCO input the sounds was very noisy. I realized that it was actually the lights causing the noise, because I have LED pot lights in my house and they must be flickering and causing the CV output to look like a square wave! Shining a flashlight with an incandescent bulb on the modules resulted in a smooth tone with no noise. Fascinating!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- this is a build involving SMD components, including a SOIC TL072. I used the iron for this one, I&amp;rsquo;ll probably break out the paste and air for a more involved build. It is a pretty good first time module for SMD, as it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have very many components at all.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Gather Your Things</title><link>https://musicminister.github.io/github.io/posts/gather-your-things/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 20:04:54 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://musicminister.github.io/github.io/posts/gather-your-things/</guid><description>Are you thinking of getting started in DIY building, but don&amp;rsquo;t know where to start? What do I need to buy to get going? Here is a list of things that I ended up buying, along with the rationale behind the purchase decisions.
Many moons ago when I was an aspiring photographer, I got some advice from a professional photographer/teacher Vincent Versace about how to choose your camera when starting out.</description><content>&lt;p>Are you thinking of getting started in DIY building, but don&amp;rsquo;t know where to start? What do I need to buy to get going? Here is a list of things that I ended up buying, along with the rationale behind the purchase decisions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many moons ago when I was an aspiring photographer, I got some advice from a professional photographer/teacher Vincent Versace about how to choose your camera when starting out. He said, &amp;ldquo;buy your last camera first.&amp;rdquo; The idea was that you should get tools that you can grow into, instead of buying something for a beginner that you will quickly outgrow, or will severely limit and frustrate you to use.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This idea of not just getting beginner tools, but something that will last and that you can grow into or grow with, has stuck with me. Not to mention the wastefulness of buying things that are too cheap, or disposable. We are making DIY synthesizers and electronics, by nature these are handmade, carefully crafted instruments, and not disposable. The tools we use should perhaps also reflect that same ethos.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyway, enough rambling! On with the list!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="entry-level-requirements">Entry-Level Requirements&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Soldering Station&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is your main tool for DIY work, and it&amp;rsquo;s worth spending slightly more for a good quality tool, if you&amp;rsquo;re able. You will need something that has interchangeable tips and a temperature setting. Something that has an iron holder keeps the hot part away from things that might burn. Like your fingers. At minimum you should have a sponge which you keep moist for wiping the tip in between components, but I have moved to the brass wire scrubber type cleaner, which I much prefer, as it doesn&amp;rsquo;t cool the tip down at all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And about those tips, most soldering irons come with a general purpose conical tip but what really works well for soldering on PCBs is a bevel tip or a chisel tip.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- Aven Tools Soldering Station With LCD Display (Model No. 17405)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- brass wire sponge soldering tip cleaner&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- bevel or chisel tips&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Magnification&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I realized pretty quickly after I started that I was going to need some kind of magnification to work on electronics. Given the age of my eyes, focusing on very small points for long periods was going to be difficult without some aid. And let&amp;rsquo;s be honest, it&amp;rsquo;s much easier to work when you can see everything clearly, so why make life hard for yourself?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are several options here, but perhaps it would be best to learn from my experience. The first magnification item I bought was a magnifying glass affixed to a pair of alligator clips, a helping hands type thing. While the clips are useful for holding things, the magnifying part is a pain to use, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to get into the right position and is very small. Not worth it, in my experience. My current magnifying device is a head worn magnifier with a headband where the magnifying portion can flip up and down as needed, but even as I write this I&amp;rsquo;m researching magnifying lamps, the kind on an arm that attaches to your table.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The headworn kind has two advantages, first is that they stay with you as you move around. The second is that they let you look with both eyes, which means you can judge the distance as you&amp;rsquo;re soldering. The downside is that the focal distance is fixed, and I find that I must get my head down relatively close to the board in order for the magnified image to be in focus. This puts me much closer to the flux fumes, and I&amp;rsquo;d rather be further away and sitting upright with better posture (see - &amp;lsquo;being old&amp;rsquo;).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So the magnifying lamp style perhaps will help me get further away from the table, and hopefully will also make the area brighter so I can see better, as well as bigger. To be determined&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Basic Tools&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- PCB Holder (helping hands or swivelling, or magnetic board with pins)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- needle nose pliers&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- fine tweezers ( with a 45 degree bend)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- flush cutter&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Solder Types&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is a lot of back and forth in the community about using solder with or without lead. I was prompted to use lead free solder at the request of my youngest daughter, so who was I to argue? Whichever solder you end up choosing, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to pay attention to the size/diameter of the wire. My everyday is 0.5mm thick, and for any SMD work I have a 0.3mm diameter spool as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- 0.5mm and 0.3mm diameter wire, 100g spool&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- Weller WSW SAC M1 (T0051388299): Composition SN3.0 AG0.5 CU3.5%&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For working with a lot of SMD parts, you may opt to use solder paste. I was recommended by another builder to try low-temp paste, which works well with a hot air rework station (see below).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- ChipQuik SMDLTLFP (Sn42/Bi57.6/Ag0.4 No-Clean T3 Solder Paste)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Silicone Soldering Mat&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At some point you&amp;rsquo;re going to want to protect your work surface, especially if you don&amp;rsquo;t have a dedicated workbench and are using a folding table in the dining room. (I&amp;rsquo;m talking about me.) I started out by salvaging a square of cork board material we had lying around, perfectly fine. I eventually upgraded to this silicon mat once I saw someone on a livestream with something like this. Get the largest one you can, unless you&amp;rsquo;re working on a really small table for some reason. This one has numerous pits for parts and bits and bobs. Very useful for keeping things contained on your table.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- SainSmart Large Anti-Static Silicone Soldering Mat, Heat Resistant 50.8cm x 35.6cm (20&amp;quot; x 14&amp;quot;)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Digital MultiMeter (DMM)&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can get something inexpensive, like an Astro AI or Klein Tools model. Buy to your budget. Look to the counts, the higher the number (6000, for example) gives you an idea of the degrees of accuracy the meter will show.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I ended up with a new multimeter after my original Canadian Tire purchase died after 20 years. I got the UNI-T UT61-E+, which is a solid midranger. UNI-T is a pretty big Chinese company. The cream of the crop is Fluke, and Brymen is a Taiwanese company, I hesitate to say knock-off, but they make a high quality multimeter as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="next-level-niceties">Next level niceties&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Hot Air Rework Station&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is something that I didn&amp;rsquo;t spend a lot on, breaking my philosophy a little bit. I picked something that looked reasonable from amazon, under $100 CAD&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Board/Flux Cleaning Tools&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- Isopropyl Alcohol (99%)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- tech dry wipes&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- art paintbrushes (natural hair)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Fume extractor&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You should be soldering with the window cracked open at the very least, so that the fumes from the flux don&amp;rsquo;t linger in your work area. I don&amp;rsquo;t have a fume extractor yet, so I can&amp;rsquo;t make a recommendation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Module Tester&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I stumbled across the &lt;a href="https://pichenettes.github.io/mutable-instruments-diy-archive/module_tester/">Mutable Instruments Module Tester PCB&lt;/a> thru a recommendation on mastodon, and if you plan on making a lot of modules or building for others, this tool is invaluable, letting you easily test the functions of most any modules. MI no longer makes these but the board schematics are freely available. I bought my PCB along with a case from amazing synth in the UK. You can read my &lt;a href="https://musicminister.github.io/github.io/posts/build-notes-amazingsynth-noodle-toaster/">Build Notes here.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Oscilloscope&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A useful tool but definitely can get expensive, and fast. In the spirit of DIY I bought a kit to assemble from JYETech, the Wave 2 which is a 2 channel digital scope. Pretty decent value, and it includes 2 probes as well. There are probably numerous old scopes on sale in your area, but unless you know what you are doing I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t recommend getting an old scope. Considering I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know how to use a scope I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to drop a ton of cash on it. Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve used this one for a while, if I ever need a nicer scope this can always serve as a backup. The model I have my eye on is the Rigol DS1054Z, so&amp;hellip; you can &lt;a href="https://www.buymeacoffee.com/music.minister/wishlist">check out my buymeacoffee&lt;/a> if you want to pitch in, ha ha. Just kidding.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Build Notes Amazing Synth Noodle Toaster</title><link>https://musicminister.github.io/github.io/posts/build-notes-amazingsynth-noodle-toaster/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 15:03:09 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://musicminister.github.io/github.io/posts/build-notes-amazingsynth-noodle-toaster/</guid><description>The Amazing Synth Noodle Toaster is an iteration on the Mutable Instruments Module Tester designed by Émilie Gillet.
Several problems were faced during the development of our Eurorack modules:
How to power and test a module during development? Bench-top power supplies are cumbersome (especially for projects requiring 3 supply rails) and standard test equipment is sometimes useless or frustrating for quantities like musical notes or V/Oct scales. On the other extreme of the scale, who would run the risk of putting a half-built prototype in a rack loaded with thousands of euros worth of modules?</description><content>&lt;p>The Amazing Synth Noodle Toaster is an iteration on the &lt;a href="https://pichenettes.github.io/mutable-instruments-diy-archive/module_tester/">Mutable Instruments Module Tester&lt;/a> designed by Émilie Gillet.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Several problems were faced during the development of our Eurorack modules:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>How to power and test a module during development? Bench-top power supplies are cumbersome (especially for projects requiring 3 supply rails) and standard test equipment is sometimes useless or frustrating for quantities like musical notes or V/Oct scales. On the other extreme of the scale, who would run the risk of putting a half-built prototype in a rack loaded with thousands of euros worth of modules?&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>What kind of setup to use for factory testing?&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>How to take a project away from the lab without carrying heaps of &amp;ldquo;dependencies&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>We solved this the Mutable Instruments way, rolling up our sleeves and designing a simple box able to provide power and all kinds of test signals (clocks, gates, CVs, audio tones) to a module. This tool is made available under cc-by-sa (hardware) and GPL (firmware) licenses.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Amazing Synth in the UK have taken this design and produced &lt;a href="https://www.amazingsynth.com/module-tester-pcb/">a nice clone of the PCB&lt;/a>, as well as a custom fitted case made from cut acrylic, in various colours.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I spent a very enjoyable day putting this together. I have since used it to test a VCA module that I put together, and it would make light work of VCO calibration, for example.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Build Notes:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- I chose the wrong kind of pin header to attach the LCD screen, so mine is sitting up off the PCB supported only by the pins. Probably not a problem as long as I don&amp;rsquo;t push hard on the screen. It&amp;rsquo;s supposed to sit on the PCB, but I like it slightly raised as it&amp;rsquo;s more visible through the opening in the case&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- The bourns trimmers on the upper right are quite tall and prevent the case from sitting down flat, it would be nice to maybe either have an opening for them so the case can screw down on the standoffs without pushing on the trimmer tops&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- the acrylic case has indented print labelling (a la D&amp;amp;D dice) so I filled them in with a white crayon, I think it looks nice, it pops against the blue colour&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- I made a mistake in putting it together, in that I did not fully fill with solder the joints for the power connector. I don&amp;rsquo;t know why, I thought I could just partially solder them but the unit wouldn&amp;rsquo;t power on when I tried it the first time. After fully filling the joints it powered on successfully&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Build Notes Zlob Vnicursal</title><link>https://musicminister.github.io/github.io/posts/build-notes-zlob-vnicursal/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:01:41 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://musicminister.github.io/github.io/posts/build-notes-zlob-vnicursal/</guid><description>Zlob Modular is the work of Keven Michael-Onur Kalaycıoğlu-Żłobnicki. Their module called the Vnicursal is 6 VCAs in an 8HP wide module, what&amp;rsquo;s not to like! Each input has a CV and then the output, either individual or there is a summed out at the bottom if you want to use it as a mixer for audio. VCAs can be used for much more than audio, and they are a must have module in every rack.</description><content>&lt;p>Zlob Modular is the work of Keven Michael-Onur Kalaycıoğlu-Żłobnicki. Their module called the &lt;a href="https://zlobmodular.com/product/vnicursal-vca/">Vnicursal&lt;/a> is 6 VCAs in an 8HP wide module, what&amp;rsquo;s not to like! Each input has a CV and then the output, either individual or there is a summed out at the bottom if you want to use it as a mixer for audio. VCAs can be used for much more than audio, and they are a must have module in every rack.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Notes:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- this is the latest revision, v666 (haha) which utilizes resistor arrays to cut down on the number of individual components, much easier to work with. More modules should start using arrays if they are sticking with thru hole designs and need lots of resistors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- this tested out great on the workbench except for channel 6, upon re-inspection I discovered I had skipped two of the leads! Haha, that&amp;rsquo;s not going to work! Did those right quick and all 6 channels working perfectly. Hurray for testing!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- Zlob has provided a very good photo build guide that you can follow along with as you go, and it shows you where each new component goes&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- it&amp;rsquo;s important to get the headers at the correct angles, precisely perpendicular to the board, otherwise you&amp;rsquo;ll have difficulty mating up the two boards after wards&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- with things like IC sockets, I like to solder one pin, and then with the iron still touching, press down (or up) with my finger to make sure the assembly is lying flat on the board, before removing the iron from the pin. Tape is required to keep the part on the board before you flip it over, but sometimes even tape can sag.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>And Just Like That</title><link>https://musicminister.github.io/github.io/posts/and-just-like-that/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 21:50:41 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://musicminister.github.io/github.io/posts/and-just-like-that/</guid><description>Ideas become reality.
I think I know exactly at what moment I decided to get into eurorack. For the uninitiated, the eurorack system of synthesizer modules has grown steadily since inception in 1995. When Dieter Doepfer shared a standard specification for his modules did he realize he would be starting a movement and a whole new interest in analog synthesizers, an antidote to the rise of the all digital instruments of the 80s?</description><content>&lt;p>Ideas become reality.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;del>I think&lt;/del> I know exactly at what moment I decided to get into eurorack. For the uninitiated, the eurorack system of synthesizer modules has grown steadily since inception in 1995. When Dieter Doepfer shared a standard specification for his modules did he realize he would be starting a movement and a whole new interest in analog synthesizers, an antidote to the rise of the all digital instruments of the 80s?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/09/28/meet-the-makers-of-modular/">&lt;em>Meet the makers of Modular&lt;/em>&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a teenager the Yamaha DX7 was a favourite synth of many. My girlfriend had one. It was cool, but I don’t think we ever programmed any sounds on it. We were basic preset players. Diving into the menus was inscrutable. We just dialed up a cool sound and got to jamming. I was more about the drums anyway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fast forward to the early 90s and I bought a KORG M1, like a quarter of a million other people. ORGAN 2 and UNIVERSE were the cool sounds, and the joystick was a like a middle finger to the separate Pitch Wheel and Mod Wheel of other synths. Ha, I can do pitch and modulation AT THE SAME TIME take that, other synths! I imagine that’s what my M1 would say. Based on built in sample playback, the Korg, like many other synths of the time, promised realistic sounds: pianos, flutes, guitars, drums, all from your keyboard!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the intervening years between then and now, I picked up a Yamaha EX5 rack, an 88-note weighted MIDI controller, and an AKAI MPD24 drum pad controller. Mostly with the idea of making music inside the box, using the DAW and virtual instrument plugins, I could pretty much have every sound I could want at my disposal. Or so I thought.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Like many (or perhaps all) of us, the pandemic spurred new depths of soul searching and reflection. What do I really want out of life, as precious as it is? A life without creative endeavours isn’t going to cut it for me, and music is my greatest passion. Whatever form it takes, I want to get back into it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A timeline:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>2022-Apr-29&lt;/em> I’m exchanging messages with a friend, a very talented musician and music producer. I see some of his for sale postings on Facebook. It’s some pretty neat synth gear.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m thinking of getting back into music and synthesis/ambient stuff, I say. I’m at the point where I’m looking at the best “first synthesizer” to buy, one where you can actually dig into everything and shape the sounds.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve been considering:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Make Noise 0-Coast and the Arturia Microfreak&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the Elektron Digitone&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the Hydrasynth&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>He suggests the Sequential Take 5, which gets added to the list.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then I say, I just discovered West Coast and Buchla. I’ve been listening to Suzanne Ciani on repeat. So &lt;strong>&lt;em>modular is not off the table&lt;/em>&lt;/strong>, I guess.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>2022-May-1&lt;/em> Finishing my tax return and I have some money coming back to me. I decide to start small and get the Arturia Microfreak.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>2022-May-11&lt;/em> Cre8audio in partnership with Pittsburgh Modular announce the East Beast, a semi modular desktop unit. I get caught up in the hype and pre-order one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>2022-May-13&lt;/em> Superbooth happens in Germany. dreadbox releases their new DYSMETRIA groovebox as a DIY kit. I can solder things, I think to myself. In recording school in our electronics course our project was to make a DI (direct injection) box from parts and a perf board. It was all point to point soldering, and we had to come up with our own cases. I think mine was one of a handful of student’s projects that actually functioned. Dreadbox says that the kit is “ideal for inexperienced DIY’ers”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>2022-May-23&lt;/em> I order a DYSMETRIA kit, along with the Patch and Tweak book, and a KOMOREBI Chorus pedal. I like how it’s semi-modular and works as a standalone box, but can be mounted into a eurorack system, you know, should that happen. At some point.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>2022-June-07&lt;/em> The package is delivered.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>2022-June-15&lt;/em> I cancel my East Beast pre-order.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>2022-June-17&lt;/em> I’ve begun building the DYSMETRIA, and now intend to fully commit to DIY my entire eurorack system. I have made purchases of the AI Synthesis VCO kit, a handful of modules from nonlinearcircuits, and a filter from MMI Modular.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>2022-July-7&lt;/em> Build is complete. Yes it took me many weeks. No it was not easy for beginners. I have it fully working though, and I post &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/uD1Zx0smYyg">a timelapse video of the build process&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So here we are. It’s February, and I’ve been with this project for 7 months. This is where I will be posting my thoughts on each build, on which modules and why, on what I’ve learned to do and to not do, and any helpful tips I’ve gained along the way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Welcome to Synth DIY Space.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>==&amp;gt; be kind make music &amp;lt;==&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>